Guide to the Foster Hall Collection, 1800-1952 CAM.FHC.2011.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Foster Family, 1800-1952; II.
  - Foster Family Sheet Music, 1800-1900; 5.
    - Bound Music of Stephen Foster from Marion Foster Welch (Musical Gift 1853), A215
      1. "I Cannot Sing tonight," (poetry by Geo. F. Banister, Esq.) 2. "Farewell Old Cottage." 3. "Eulalie," (written by H.S. Cornwell) 4. "Maggie by my Side." 5. "Once I Loved Thee, Mary Dear," (written by Wm. Cullen Crookshaft) 6. "Mary Loves the Flowers." 7. "Lily Ray." 8. "The Voice of By Gone Days." 9. "I Would Not Die in Springtime," arr. by Milton Moore. 10. "I Would not Die in Summertime." 11. "Molly! Do You Love Me?" (Title page only) 12. "Ah! May the Red Rose Live Alway." 13. "The Spirit of My Song," (poetry by Metta Victoria Fuller) 14. "Give the Stranger Happy Cheer." 15. "Mother, Thou'rt Faithful to Me." 16. "Sweetly She Sleeps, my Alice Fair," (written by Charles G. Eastman) 17. "Laura Lee." 18. "Stay Summer Breath." 19. "Summer Longings." 20. "What Must a Fairy's Dream Be." 21. "There's a Good time Coming," (lines from the London Daily News) 22. "Wilt thou be Gone Love," (subject from Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet) 23. "The Hour for Thee and Me." 24. "Turn Not Away!" 25. "The Village Bells," (Polka) 26. "Soiree Polka."
  - Obituaries, 1800-1937; 6.
    This subseries includes obituaries of Stephen Foster's wife, Jane, and sister, Charlotte.
    - Newspaper Notice of Jane Denny Foster's death, January 17, 1903; A300
    - Obituary of Charlotte Foster, October 20, 1829; A302
    - Charlotte Foster's Obituary (handwritten), undated; C454
  - Records, 1823-1880; 7.
    This subseries includes business and personal records for Stephen Foster's immediate family members. Of particular note are the five ledgers/diaries created by Morrison Foster for his business concerns in the Pittsburgh area, some of which include notation of Stephen Foster expenses.
    - Buchanan Glee Club Minute Book, 1856; A229
    - William Foster's Record Book, 1839-1851; A8
    - Deed to lot in Lawrenceville, 1823; C391
    - Bills to Mrs. Foster from William Davidson for fabric goods, August, 1848; C481
    - Photostats of letter and receipt for the North Branch Division, Penn Canal and Wyoming Lines, 1843; C495
    - Copy of Will of Henrietta Thornton, February 16, 1877; C523
    - Henry Wick's Will, undated; C525
    - Copy of Lease from Morrison Foster to William B. Foster, April 28, 1846; C526
    - Copy of account book pages showing payouts from Thomas Wick's estate, 1840; C527
    - Dunning Foster's will, June 9, 1847; C538
    - Morrison Foster lists and receipts for expenses at the time of Stephen Foster's death, January 25, 1855; C548
    - Receipt for Dunning Foster's funeral, March 31, 1856; C553
    - Morrison Foster's Odd Fellows certificate, undated; C709
    - Deed between First Methodist Protestant Church & William Foster, Jr., September 7, 1844; C712
    - Deed between Christopher Fallon and William Foster, Jr., December 24, 1852; C713
    - Articles of agreement between Edward Stephens and William B. Foster, Jr., July 16, 1835; C714
    - Deed between Edward Stephens & wife and William B. Foster, Jr., April 29, 1843; C715
    - Deed between Thomas Salter and wife and Edward Stephens and wife, September 28, 1835; C716
    - Railroad subscription list, 1847; C718
    - An Act to Incorporate the PA Railroad Co., April 13, 1846; C719
    - By-laws and charter of the PA Railroad Co., 1847; C720
    - Receipt for $250.00 from William D. Kudz, June 2, 1857; C722a.
      PA Railroad receipt for services. Includes cover note.
    - Receipt for $50,000, May 19, 1857; C722b.
      PA Railroad receipt for services.
    - Receipt for $1762.25, May 28, 1859; C722c.
    - Receipt for $100 from Thomas B. Franklin, May 26, 1857; C722d.
    - Receipt for $613.00, undated; C722e.
    - Receipt for $2425, May 27, 1857; C722f.
    - William B. Foster, Jr.'s certificate for the Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1831; C723
    - Bylaws of the PA Railroad Co., 1847; C724
      Bylaws of PA Railroad Co.
    - An act to incorporate the Foster Coal and Iron Company, 1860; C725
      Act to incorporate the Foster Coal & Iron Co.
    - Resolution of the PA Railroad board of directors giving leave of absence to William B. Foster, Jr., November 15, 1855; C726
      Resolution of PA Railroad Board of Directors giving leave of absence to William B. Foster, Jr.
    - Settlement between bank of Harrisburg and the estate of William B. Foster, Jr., September 24, 1861; C727
      From J. Edgar Thomson settlement of Endorsement for William B. Foster, Jr.
    - Jefferson Club Minutes, 1880; C730
    - Buchanan Glee Club Constitution and Minute Book, 1856; C731
    - Annual assembly subscribers names, 1854; C732
    - IOU from John Halbergshalt, October 5, 1831; C774a.
    - IOU from James L. Miltin for $1831, June 24, 1828; C774b.
    - IOU from James G. Stacey for $403.00, October 13, 1828; C774c.
    - IOU from John Steel & Co. for $555, July 25, 1828; C774d.
    - IOU from Edie Poole for $303.47, May 14, 1826; C774e.
    - IOU from Edie Poole from $306.41, May 14, 1826; C774f.
    - IOU from J.R. Brincelle for $611.83, January 4, 1826; C774g.
    - IOU from Josiah Gould for $1890.65, September 26, 1827; C774h.
    - IOU from Hudson Foster for $150, April 27, 1833; C774i.
    - IOU from C. Purdy for $63.13, February 1, 1830; C774j.
    - IOU from J. Foster Sheppard for $53.25, August 23, 1824; C774k.
    - List of certificates adding up to $4900, May 9, 1829; C774l.
    - IOU from Heplund for $30,000 plus interest, undated; C774m.
    - IOU from B. Patterson for railroad shares, May 13; C774n.
    - IOU to William B. Foster, Jr., from Eck for $2.00, September 13, 1845; C871a
    - IOU from Israel Sallade to William Foster, Jr., for ten dollars, March 28, 1845; c871b
    - IOU from J. Heron Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., for ten dollars, April 12, 1845; c871c
    - IOU from John Ecke to William Foster, Jr., for $25, June 13, 1846; c871d
    - IOU from D.A. [?] to William B. Foster for $5.00, March 14, 1854; c871e
    - IOU from Donnelly & Co. to William B. Foster, Jr., for $400, May6, 1848; c871f
    - IOU from S. Billy to William B. Foster, Jr., for $80, September 13, 1843; C871g
    - Morrison Foster's Pocket Ledger for Pollard McCormick, 1842-1846; D323
    - Morrison Foster's Ledger/diary, 1847-1849; D324
    - Morrison Foster's Ledger/Diary, 1849-1854; D325
      Entry related to Stephen Foster's boarding cost flagged.
    - Morrison Foster's Check ledger, 1853-1857; D326
      Pages related to Stephen Foster monies are flagged. includes a complete version of James G. Drake's song "Tom Breeze."
    - Morrison Foster's Ledger/Diary, 1852-1853; D327
    - Morrison Foster's Ledger/Diary, 1855; D328
    - Morrison Foster's Ledger/Diary, 1844-1847; D408
      Small ledger Diary with the date range '44-45 - 46-47 written on the cover. First page has Morrison Foster March 19, 1844 written vertically in ink.
  - Maps, 1788-1840; 8.
    This subseries includes Pennsylvania maps there were significant to Foster's immediate family.
    - PA railroad survey map Harrisburg to Pittsburgh, 1839-1840; C717
    - Map of lands belonging to William B. Foster, Jr., Youngstown, Ohio, undated; C734
    - Map of Franklin College, 1788; C773
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, Programs and Pamphlets, 1800-1937; 9.
    This subseries includes newspaper articles, collected by Morrison Foster, about the efforts to memorizalize Stephen Foster, Pennsylvania history and other Foster family members.
    - "The North American: Central Pennsylvania Railroad", January 21, 1847; C728
    - "Appointment of W.B. Foster", September 25, 1849; C711a.
      Stored in the envelope "Newspaper clippings about William B. Foster, Jr."
    - "Engineer Appointed," Bradford Reporter, September 19, 1849; C711b.
    - "Letter to the editor from James Cameron", October 7, 1846; C711c.
    - "Duty of the Canal Commissioners", Feburary 15, 1847; C711d.
    - "Canal Commissioner", undated; C711e.
    - "Foster Memorial: How the Well-known song, Nelly was a Lady, Was Presented to the Public", June 23, 1895; C764a.
    - "Foster Memorial: The Composer Did Much Toward Freeing the Negro", June, 1895; C764b.
    - "10,000 Pay Homage to Foster in Schenley Park Celebration: Winter's Eulogizes Composer," Pittsburgh Gazette Times, July 6, 1926; C766
    - "The Foster Memorial: Monument to Pittsburg Composer --- It May be Placed in Highland Park," The Pittsburg Leader, May 21, 1899; C767
    - "The Foster Memorial: concerts to be given in aid of the Monument fund", August 19, 1895; C764c.
    - "The Foster Memorial: Pertinent remarks by a prominent citizen", August 18, 1895; C764d.
    - "Foster Memorial: arrangements for the annual benefit of the homeopathic hospital", August 22, 1895; C764e.
    - "Foster Memorial: Pittsburg Composer's melodies will be sun at a grand concert at Irwin", August 14, 1895; C764f.
    - "Foster Memorial: A Cleveland Merchant's Pertinent Remarks", August 8, 1895; C764g.
    - "Foster Memorial: the similarity of sentiment is against pointed out", July 27, 1895; C764h.
    - "Foster Memorial: A Pittsburgher's Account of his visit to Mexico", July 6, 1895; C764i.
    - "Foster Memorial: the Great Song Writer Popular from the Start", July 28, 1895; C764j.
    - "Foster Memorial: Another liberal contribution to the fund", July 20, 1895; C764k.
    - "Foster Memorial: the movement is receiving most hearty support", July 1895; C764l.
    - "Foster Memorial: Independence Day is Over. Now, Let the public aid the monument fund", undated; C764m.
    - "The Foster Memorial: contributions to the fund received this morning", August 12, 1895; C764n.
    - "Foster Memorial: Contributions still coming in for the fund", July 21, 1895; C764o.
    - "Stephen C. Foster as Man and Musician," The Pittsburg Press, September 12, 1900; C764p.
    - "Tribute to Foster: Noted sculptors submit designs for the monument", May 10, 1899; C764q.
    - "Foster Memorial: Sir Edwin Arnold gives his impressions of the Beautiful Swanee River", July 14, 1895; C764r.
    - "Foster Memorial: motive that prompted the press to advocate and support the movement", June 24, 1895; C764s.
    - "Foster Memorial: Pupils of the Allen School have set the pace", undated; C764t.
    - "Foster Memorial: there is no doubt about the popularity of the Pittsburg writer's songs", June 22, 1895; C764u.
    - "Foster Memorial: the fund is slowly but surely growing", July 18, 1895; C764v.
    - "The Foster Memorial: reminiscences of a lively political campaign", July 11, 1895; C764w.
    - "Power of a Foster Melody", August 16, 1903; C764x.
    - "Foster Memorial: A concert will be given at Irwin next month," The Pittsburg Press, July 12, 1895; C764y.
    - "Foster Memorial: Independence Day is the anniversary of the birth of the composer", July 3, 1895; C764z.
    - "Foster's Melodies: will be sung by grand chorus to-morrow night," Pittsburg Press, June 6, 1895; C764aa.
    - "Monument to Foster: his quaint negro melodies," Chicago Times, June 30, 1895; C764bb.
    - "Foster Memorial: Pittsburg Composer's melodies all the rage", July 7, 1895; C764cc.
    - "Foster Memorial: an old resident's recollections of the composer", June 1895; C764dd.
    - "Foster Memorial: an interesting incident in the composer's life", July 16, 1895; C764ee.
    - "Foster Memorial: what a New York Musician thinks of the project", June, 1895; C764ff.
    - "Foster Memorial: Don't wait for others to subscribe to the fund", June, 1895; C764gg.
    - "Foster Memorial: an incident at Lancaster that resulted in a contribution to the fund", July 1895; C764hh.
    - "The Foster Memorial: an interested letter from a Youngstown merchant", August 17, 1895; C764ii.
    - "A new Foster song: Mrs. J.J. Vandergrift has the original manuscript", December 11, 1895; C764jj.
    - "The Foster Memorial: A Pittsburgher heard of it while in Europe", August 11, 1895; C764kk.
    - "Foster Memorial: Need for complete collection of the composer's songs", July 13, 1895; C764ll.
    - "Foster Memorial: the interest in the movement is unabated", July 16, 1895; C764mm.
    - "Suwanee River and other American Ballads", undated; C764nn.
    - "Foster Memorial: Incidents in the Composer's life recalled by prominent merchant", July 1895; C764oo.
    - "The Foster Fund: Pittsburg Ladies Deeply Interested in the Movement", July 10, 1895; C764pp.
    - "Foster Memorial: A general donation from Heeren Bros. & Co.", September 6, 1895; C764qq.
    - Partial article about Marion Foster Welsh, undated; C764rr.
    - "New Song by Foster: finding of a long-lost melody by Pittsburg's Composer," The Pittsburg Dispatch, December 11, 1895; C764ss.
    - Foster Memorial: A Volume of His songs will soon be issued, June 28, 1895; C764tt
    - Partial article about "Where Is Thy Spirit Mary?", Undated; C764uu
    - Partial article about "Hard Times Come Again No More", no date; C764vv
    - "Stephen C. Foster -- In Memoriam", no date; C764ww
    - Pamphlet, "Foster Melodies to be Sung at the Dedication of the Stephen C. Foster Monument," compliments of the Pittsburg Press, 1900; C769a.; 2 copies.
    - "Unveiling of Foster Monument Memorial at Highland Park this Afternoon," The Pittsburg Press, September 12, 1900; C769b.
    - "Unveiling of the Foster Memorial Photographically Told," The Pittsburgh Press, September 16, 1900; C769c.
    - "Surviving Relatives of Stephen C. Foster," The Pittsburg Press, September 2, 1900; C769d.
    - "To Whom Thanks Are Due", September 12, 1900; C769e.
    - "The Monument and stand as they appeared prior to the unveiling ceremonies," The Pittsburg Press, September 12, 1900; C769f.
    - "The Stephen C. Foster Memorial," The Pittsburg Press, September 12, 1900; C769g.
    - "In Pittsburgh, 100 Years Ago, A Great Minstrel Was Born," The Pittsburgh Sunday Post, July 4, 1926; C771a.; two copies
    - "U.S. to Pay Tribute this July 4 to Stephen C. Foster," The Detroit News, July 4, 1926; C771b.
    - "Monuments in Pittsburg and Allegheny", undated; C771c.
    - "Foster Memorial, a concert to be Given in Aid of the Fund by Southern Jubilee Singers," Pittsburg Press, June 14, 1895; C771d.
    - "Foster Memorial a Project that should appeal to the heart of every lover of music," Pittsburg Press, June 9, 1895; C771e.
    - "Nephew Says he was Raised on the Immortal Music and Lyrics of Pittsburgh's Great Bard," by William Barclay Foster, Pittsburgh Post, July 4, 1926; C771g.
      Special section devoted to Foster, includes articles "His Widow's Memories of Foster's Life are Recalled by Granddaughter," by Jessie Welsh Rose
    - "Foster Memorial: Other cities taking an interest in the project," Pittsburgh Press, June 5, 1895; C771h.
    - "Stephen Foster A Maker of Folk Songs," Etude, 1913; C772a.
    - Ad for Foster Memorial Service, January 13, 1923; C772b.
    - Station KQV Programs, undated; C772c.
    - "Foster lauded by W.J. Bryan: Purchases first batch of postal cards at Kiwanis club meeting", undated; C772d.
    - "Many Tributes Paid to Memory of Foster Today", January 13, 1923; C772e.
    - "The Optimist", February 6, 1914; C772f.
    - "Musical Comments: Milligan's Life of Stephen Foster", Sept. 26, 1920; C772g.
    - "Anniversary Observed: Stephen C. Foster's Life Reviewed at Lawrenceville Meeting", undated; C772h.
    - "In Memoriam: Stephen Collins Foster", undated; C772i.
    - "Old-song Society Celebrates First Anniversary", July 26, 1931; C772j.
    - "Stephen Foster's Piano Now Rests in Famous Musician's Old Home", May 1, 1926; C772k.
    - "From Dispatch Readers: Foster in Pittsburg", undated; C772l.
    - "Letter to the Editor: Great Admirer of Foster," Chronicle Telegraph, January 10, 1923; C772m.
    - "July 4th is Anniversary of Birth of Pittsburgh Songster, Stephen Foster," The Pittsburgh Gazette Times, June 29, 1919; C772n.; two copies included.
    - Stephen C. Foster and His Songs, October 3, 1897; C772o.
    - "The Theater," Detroit Free Press, June 13; C772p.
    - "Songs of the Heart -- They Are Not Written Now-a-Days," The Pittsburgh Gazette Times, December 5, 1909; C772q.
    - "Some Old Songs and Their Stories" by William Armstrong, undated; C772r.
    - "Pittsburgh Pays Warm Tribute to Stephen Collins Foster," Pittsburgh Gazette Times, January 14, 1923; C772s.
    - "Exercises to Mark Placing of Wreath on Foster's Grave", undated; C772t.
    - "Some Unconsidered Trifles," by E.W. Lightner, The Pittsburg Dispatch, July 14, 1921; C772u.; Two copies enclosed.
    - "Should Have Monument on River He Made So Famous," by Percy F. Smith, undated; C772v.; two copies enclosed.
    - "Songs that Never Die: No. 28 "My Old Kentucky Home," by Frederic Reddall, Pittsburgh Sun, undated; C772w.
    - "Songs that Never Die: No. 24 "Swanee River," Pittsburgh Sun, November 27, 2009; C772x.
    - "To Play Foster Music", undated; C772y.
    - "U.S. Popular Music is Declared Best", undated; C772z.
    - "Worthy A Bit of Sentiment", undated; C772aa.
    - "Famous Song Oddly Named: Attorney Watson Tells How Foster Selected "Suwanee" for Title", undated; C772bb.
    - "Utters Fine Pittsburg Panegyric," Pittsburgh Dispatch, undated; C772cc.
    - "May Add Additional Songs to Foster List" by William R. Mitchel, 1930; C772dd.
    - "Old Folks at Home sung at Foster Kin Funeral", July 3, 1929; C772ee.
    - "Bridegroom Wrote Old Kentucky Home," Detroit Free Press, June 28, 1931; C772ff.
    - "Sight of Yanks on German Soil Stuns Populace," by Burr Price, undated; C772gg.
    - "Participant in Pageant", undated; C772hh.
    - "Free Organ Recital", undated; C772ii.
    - "Stephen C. Foster and His Songs," Pittsburgh Post, October 3, 1897; C772jj.
    - "Democratic State Convention", undated; C841a.
    - Cleveland Daily Herald, October 16, 1863; C841b.
    - "The Question of Opening Monumental Park", undated; C841c.
    - Morning Post, Vol. XIII No. 25, February 11, 1860; C841d.
    - Pittsburgh Post, February 8, 1860; C842a.
    - Clipping of photo of A.J. Cassatt, President of the PA Railroad System, October 28, 1902; C842b.
    - Pittsburgh Post, February 8, 1860; C842c.
    - New York Daily News, July 6, 1863; C843a.
    - The Pittsburgh Evening Chronicle, April 15, 1865; C843b.
    - Daily Cleveland Herald, June 16, 1863; C843c.
    - Daily Ohio Statesman, March 24, 1864; C843d.
    - "Lilly Sends Copies of First Editions of Foster Songs to 1,000 Libraries," The Indianapolis Star, January 10, 1934; C844
    - "Early Journalism in Pittsburg: Leaves from the shelves of the Late Judge Parker's Library," The Pittsburg Leader, January 8, 1888; C900a.
    - "A Pioneer Supplement to the Gazette," The Pittsburgh Gazette, January 4, 1903; C900b.
    - "Abandonment of the Allegheny Arsenal," The Pittsburgh Gazette, January 12, 1902; C900c.
    - "The Trail of Forbes' Army Through Pittsburgh," The Pittsburgh Gazette, March 8, 1903; C900d.
    - "Of the Main Line of the Public Works of Pennsylvania," Daily Pittsburg Dispatch, June 24, 1857; C900e.
    - Daily Pittsburgh Dispatch, June 11, 1857; C900f.
    - "Pilots Before 1858," The Pittsburg Leader, December 1, 1889; C900g.
    - "Pencil Sketch of the Mayors," Pittsburgh Evening Chronicle, December 4, 1867; C900h.
    - "That Naughty School Question -- 'First Ward' Speaketh", November 16, 1871; C900i.
    - "La Fayette's visit Here Cause of Controversy," The Pittsburgh Gazette, July 1, 1917; C900j.
      handwritten correction to the article.
    - "Views from the Hilltops," The Pittsburg Press, April 30, 1899; C900k.
    - "An Immortal Balladist," Detroit Free Press, July 4, 1926; C901a.
    - "Brought Renown to Pittsburgh", undated; C901b.
    - "Legends Obscure Foster, Declares His Biographer", undated; C901c.
    - "Trade Balance Puzzle," Pittsburg Press, October 18, 1901; C902a.
    - Letter to the Editor from Morrison Foster "That Trade Balance "Puzzle", October 18, 1901; C902b.
    - "London Has it Now," Pittsburg Press, October 24, 1901; C902c.
    - "A Correspondent's Exceptions," Pittsburgh Press, October 20, 1901; C902d.
    - "Davis Answers Black", August 8, 1883; C913a.
    - "The Real Buchanan," The Philadelphia Press, August 12, 1883; C913b.
    - "A Great Song-Writer and His Songs" in The Way, Vol. XLIV, November 25, 1922; C883a.
    - Pamphlet, "Pittsburg and the South: A Relationship Made Imperishable by the "Life and Songs" of Stephen Collins Foster", September 10-28th, 1912; C883b.
    - Pamphlet, "Foster Melodies Medley in Memory of Judge John Rowan", undated; C883c.
    - Blue Line print for "Foster Melodies Medley for Judge John Rowan", undated; C883d.
    - Sheet music for "Foster's Melodies Medley," by Winifred Callahan, 1921; C883e.
    - "Stephen Foster (memo for 1894)" by Haniel Long, Scribner's Magazine, October, 1933; C883f.
    - Souvenir Program, "Carnegie Music Hall, Pittsburg, Stephen C. Foster Concerts for the Benefit of the Homeopathic Hospital and the Foster Memorial", November 15 and 16, 1895; C883g.
    - Postcard of Foster monument, Highland Park, August 30, 1905; C883h.
    - Pamphlet, "Indianapolis Public Schools Educational Museum, Stephen Foster Exhibit, No. 54", undated; C883i.
    - Telegram from The Southernaires to Evelyn Foster Morneweck, October 9, 1931; C883j.
    - Program, "Selections from The Plantation Melodies of Stephen Collins Foster Sung at the Annual Banquet of the Pennsylvania Scotch-Irish Society, Philadelphia", February 13, 1896; C883k.
    - Invitation from the Civil Club of Allegheny county to Evelyn Morneweck for the 68th anniversary commemoration events for the death of Stephen Foster, January 6, 1932; C883l.
    - Pamphlet, "A Hand-Book of History containing an Authentic Genealogic Chart of Stephen Collins Foster and His Immediate Family" by Matilda Orr Hays, 1932; C883m.
    - Letter from John Wilson Townsend to Evelyn Foster Morneweck, September 14, 1932; C883n.
    - Three typed notes from John Wilson Townsend to Evelyn Foster Morneweck, June 23, 1933; C883o.
    - Typed transcript of poem "The five 'nice young men'" by Stephen Foster, May 6, 1845; C883p.
    - Program for "Program Presented by the Stephen Collins Foster Committee of the Civic Club of Allegheny County for the 68th Anniversary of the Death of Stephen C. Foster", January 13, 1932; C883q.
    - "Pictorial Biography of Stephen Collins Foster," Musical Courier, 1930; C915; 2 copies
    - "Democratic Ticket" poem by W.H. Attree, 1844; C492a.
    - "The Popular Credo" poem by Charles P. Shiras, circa 1870s; C492b.
  - William B. Foster Papers, 1814-1955; 10.
    This subseries includes the business papers of Stephen Foster's father, William B. Foster, Sr. It consists of corrrespondence, papers related to court cases, the War of 1812, the establishment of Lawrenceville, and materials general by Morrison Foster related to his attempts to settle his father's estate.
    - War of 1812 Correspondence and Transactions, 1.
      This section contains the correspondence of William B. Foster during his years as a commissary agent for the U.S. Army during the War of 1812. Most of these papers deal with supply and military sustenance issues; occasionally a letter emerges that tells of William's amicable relationship with several of these military officers.
      - Letter from Commissary General's Office to William Foster, May 21, 1814; D.1
      - General Order: Adjutant and Inspector General's Office, August 4, 1814; D.2
      - Accounting of Purchases by William Foster and account of William Lyman, August 31, 1814; D.3
      - Letter from Commissary General's office to William Foster, October 11, 1814; D.4
      - Invoice of purchases from John Mclean, signed by Captain Woolley, October 20, 1814; D.5